H-He beat him...
O-Onu yendi...
H-He beat Captain Kuro!
K-Kaptan Kuro'yu yendi.
Even the Marines were no match for Kuro of a Thousand Plans!
Denizciler bile "Bin Planlı Kuro"ya bir şey yapamadı.
But he really beat him!
Ama o başardı!
Just who are you?!
Sen de kimsin?!
Monkey D. Luffy.
Monkey D. Luffy.
I'd never lose to a pirate who ditches his name and runs from the sea.
Adını silip denizden kaçan bir korsana asla yenilmem.
The only time a pirate should abandon his name is when he dies!
Gerçek bir korsan, öleceği güne dek adını terketmez.
Luffy?! Nope, doesn't ring a bell...
Luffy mi? Hiç duymadım...
Remember my name for the rest of your lives!
Hayatın boyunca adımı unutma!
I'm the man who's gonna be King of the Pirates!
Ben, Korsanlar Kralı olacağım!
This guy's...
O herif...
Take him and go!
Alın şunu da defolun!
Never come back!
Bir daha sakın gelmeyin!
Run!
Kaçın!
You did good.
İyi iş çıkardın.
Weigh anchor! Hurry!
Demir alın! Çabuk!
I guess even you would collapse after all you've been through...
Bunca şeyden sonra senin de bitkin düşmen normal sanırım.
So...
Söyle...
what were you mad about earlier?
Az önce neye sinirlendin?
I hate them.
Onlardan hoşlanmıyorum.
They're wrong.
Yanılıyorlar.
That's not how crewmates are supposed to act.
Arkadaşlara o gözle bakılmamalı.
What're you talking about?
Neden bahsediyorsun?
It's in their nature.
Hep böyledir işte.
Pirates aren't exactly the merry bunch you make them out to be.
Korsanlar, düşündüğün kadar asil değiller.
I want some meat.
Et istiyorum.
You're unbelievable!
İnanılmazsın!
Can you keep everything that's happened here a secret?
Olan biten her şeyi gizli tutabilir misiniz?
What?! Keep it a secret?!
Ne?! Gizli mi?!
Why would we do that?!
Niye böyle bir şey yapalım?!
Yeah! After we just fought for the sake of the village!
Evet! Köyü korumak için hayatımız pahasına savaştık.
I bet it'll change how everyone thinks of you!
Bu, insanların sana bakış açısını değiştirecek!
You'll be the village hero!
Köyümüzün kahramanı olacaksın!
– Yeah!
– Evet!
Usopp, you need to clear up this misunderstanding.
Usopp-san, herkesle tüm bu yanlış anlaşılmaları düzeltmelisin.
What misunderstanding?
Ne yanlış anlaması?
All they did was call me a liar, same as always.
Sadece her zamanki gibi yalan söylediğimi düşünecekler.
Why go and scare everyone when it's been settled?
Her şey bitmişken neden herkesi korkutalım?
This was a one-time thing.
Bu, tek seferlik bir şeydi.
No pirate's going out of their way to attack a remote village like this one again.
Hiçbir korsan, böyle ücra bir köye bir daha saldırmaz.
I'm just going to pretend that nothing ever happened.
Hiçbir şey olmamış gibi davranacağım.
It was all a lie.
Hepsi bir yalandı.
But of course, I can't force you.
Sizi zorlamayacağım, ama...
No, we can do it!
Hayır, bunu yapabiliriz!
If it's for the good of the village!
Köyün iyiliği içinse...!
I agree!
Katılıyorum!
Me too! I'll never say a word, ever!
Ben de! Tek kelime etmeyeceğim, asla!
Kaya...
Kaya...
Will that be hard for you?
Sen şeytana uyacak mısın?
No.
Hayır.
Where could Usopp be this morning?
Usopp-kun niye bu sabah ortalıkta yok?
It just doesn't feel right... I can't get motivated.
Bir şeyler doğru hissettirmiyor. Motive olamıyorum.
Mommy...
Anneciğim...
Is Mr. Liar not coming today?
Bay Yalancı bugün gelmeyecek mi?
That lying runt...
Seni küçük yalancı...
Why is he so late?!
neden geciktin?!
You think maybe I was a bit too harsh yesterday?
Acaba dün biraz fazla mı sert davrandım?
I'm sure he'll be back to his old tricks tomorrow!
Yarın eski hâline dönecektir.
Just watch.
Eminim...
Thanks!
Teşekkürler.
I wouldn't have been able to protect the village without you guys!
Siz olmadan bu köyü koruyamazdım!
What're you talking about?
Ne saçmalıyorsun sen?
If it weren't for you, I wouldn't have done a thing!
Eğer hayatını riske atmasaydın, ben hiçbir şey yapmazdım!
Me neither!
Ben de!
Who cares about that?
Kimin umurunda?
I made a killing!
Biraz hazine buldum!
Thanks to this incident,
Bu olay sayesinde,
I've finally made a decision.
bir karara vardım.
Captain Usopp! What was it you wanted to talk to us about?
Kaptan Usopp! Bizimle ne konuşmak istemiştiniz?
You guys fought well against those Black Cat Pirates!
Sizler, o Kara Kedi Korsanlarıyla iyi savaştınız!
As captain, I feel very proud!
Kaptanınız olarak, sizinle gurur duyuyorum!
We overcame our biggest and greatest battle since we formed
Kuruluşumuzdan beri en büyük ve en zor savaşımızı kazandık.
the Usopp Pirates five years ago, when you guys were just four years old!
Beş yıl önce siz dört yaşındayken, Usopp Korsanları şekillendi.
– Yeah!
– Evet!
So, I know this is sudden...
Biliyorum, bu ani oldu...
but I've decided to set out to sea by myself!
ama tek başıma denize açılmaya karar verdim!
I'm gonna be a real pirate!
Gerçek bir korsan olmak istiyorum!
I'd always been unsure of whether I should stay or go...
Burada kalıp kalmamam konusunda hep kararsızdım...
But... when I met them, I finally made up my mind!
Ama... Onlarla tanıştıktan sonra, kararımı verdim!
I feel that as a man, I must set out onto the vast ocean!
Bir erkek olarak, şu engin denizi kucaklamalıyım!
So...
Bu yüzden...
I'm leaving this village!
Bu köyden ayrılıyorum!
The pirate flag is calling me!
Korsan bayrağı beni çağırıyor! Başka ne sebep istersin ki?!
Captain! You're lying, right?!
Kaptan! Yalan söylüyorsun, değil mi?!
You're lying again, right?!
Başka bir yalan daha, değil mi?!
It's way too sudden!
Bu çok ani oldu!
Don't you love this village, Captain?!
Bu köyü sevmiyor musun, Kaptan?
What'll happen to the Usopp Pirates?!
Usopp Korsanları'na ne olacak?!
You've been good to me, guys...
Benim için bir şey yapmanızı istiyorum.
I plan to leave without telling the villagers.
Köylülere söylemeden ayrılmayı planlıyorum.
Give them my regards.
Onlara selamlarımı iletin.
No...
Olmaz...
I don't want to!
İstemiyorum!
Don't go, Captain!
Gitme, Kaptan!
Do you remember this place?
Burayı hatırlıyor musunuz?
This is where we first met.
İlk burada tanışmıştık.
All done!
Tamamdır!
Mr. Liar!
Bay Yalancı!
Who are you guys?! Don't act all buddy-buddy with me!
Siz kimsiniz?! Bana, dostmuşuz gibi davranmayın!
But you're famous!
Çünkü sen ünlüsün!
Yeah, you're like a celebrity...
Evet, sen ünlü birisin.
I see!
Anlıyorum!
Finally some respect! So, people are now calling me Captain Usopp!
Demek, herkes bana Kaptan Usopp diyerek saygı duyuyor!
Everyone calls you Usopp the Liar!
Herkes ona Yalancı Usopp diyor!
Alright! From this day forth, you're members of the Usopp Pirates too!
Tamam! Bugünden itibaren siz de Usopp Korsanları'nın birer parçasısınız!
– What?
— Ne?
Don't "what" me!
Bana "ne" çekmeyin!
A lot's happened, huh?
Çok şey yaşadık, ha?
It's Cerberus!
Bu, Kerberus!
Scare it away!
Korkutup kaçırın!
A dragon!
Bir ejderha!
Let's capture it!
Hadi yakalayalım!
Flour Star!
Un Yıldızı!
You're amazing, Captain!
Harikasınız, Kaptan!
But of course!
Elbette öyleyim!
I am a brave warrior of the sea!
Sonuçta denizin cesur savaşçısıyım!
We don't wanna hear about the good old days!
Geçmişten bahsedişini duymak istemiyoruz!
Yeah! We don't wanna hear about that!
Evet! Bunu duymak istemiyoruz!
This isn't like you, Captain!
Kendin gibi davranmıyorsun, Kaptan!
Why are you saying this stuff now?!
Neden şimdi bunları söylüyorsun?!
It's almost like you're...
Bu... sanki...
You're so stupid, Captain!
"Aptal Kaptan" gibi!
Stupid!
Aptal!
What are your ambitions in life?!
Hayattaki hedefleriniz ne?!
To run a pub!
Bar işletmek!
To be a master carpenter!
Usta bir marangoz olmak!
To be a novelist!
Roman yazarı olmak!
Then swear right here that you'll continue on each of your paths...
Hayallerinizin ateşinin sönmesine asla izin vermeyin!
and never let the fires of your ambitions go out!
Azimle kendi yolunuzda yürüyeceğinize yemin etmelisiniz!
As of today...
Bugünden itibaren...
the Usopp Pirates...
Usopp Korsanları...
are disbanded!
dağılmıştır!
Well, we've eaten. We should get going now.
Yemeğimizi yedik. Sanırım gitme vakti.
Yeah...
Evet...
There you are!
İşte buradasınız!
Hey, miss!
Selam, hanımefendi!
You're out of bed already?
Dışarıda olmanız uygun mu?
Yes...
Evet...
My illness this past year was due to the grief from losing my parents.
Geçen yılki hastalığım,
Usopp's been there to cheer me up, but...
Usopp-san beni neşelendirmek için çok çaba harcadı.
I can't stay coddled forever!
Artık korunarak yaşayamam!
I've prepared a little something for you as a token of my gratitude!
Size minnettarlığımın bir göstergesi olarak ufak bir şey hazırladım!
Please accept it!
Lütfen kabul edin!
All packed...
Bitirdim.
Guess it's farewell to this house, too!
Az sonra bu eve de veda edeceğim.
What?!
Ne?!
What the...? I can't get out!
Ne...? Çıkamıyorum!
Damn it!
Kahretsin!
A caravel!
"Karavel" bu!
Can we really have this?!
Bu gerçekten bizim için mi?!
Yes, it's all yours!
Evet, lütfen kullanın!
It's a slightly older model, but I designed it myself!
Biraz eski moda da olsa, bunu tasarlayan benim.
A carvel-built caravel, with lateen sails and a central stern rudder...
Karvel yapım, üçgen yelkenli ve kıçta merkez dümenli bir karavel:
the Going Merry!
Going Merry'yle tanışın!
Let me explain the running rigging!
Donanımını açıklayayım.
First, about the clew-garnet yard adjustment–
Öncelikle iskota ve seren ayarından bahsedelim—
No, no!
Ah, hayır, hayır!
You can explain the ship stuff to me!
Gemi işlerini sadece bana anlatın!
What a nice ship!
Harika bir gemi!
Especially the front—it's so cool!
Özellikle de ön taraf, çok havalı!
We've loaded it with everything we thought you might need on your voyage.
İhtiyacınız olan her şey gemiye yüklendi.
Thanks! It leaves everything to be desired!
Teşekkür ederim, gerçekten çok minnettarsınız!
It's "nothing to be desired," you idiot.
"Çok düşüncelisiniz" olacak, salak!
Stop this thing!
Durdurun şunu!
Usopp!
Usopp-san!
What's he doing?
Ne yapıyor o?
Let's just stop him.
Neyse, durduralım onu.
He's about to collide with the ship.
Doğruca gemiye gidiyor.
Th-Thanks...
T-Tetekküller...
Yeah.
Rica.
So... you're really going out to sea, Usopp?
Demek, gerçekten denize açılıyorsun, Usopp-san?
Yeah.
Evet.
I figured I should get going before I lose my nerve.
Cesaretimi yitirmeden ayrılsam iyi olacak.
Don't stop me now.
Beni durdurma.
I won't.
Durdurmayacağım.
I could just tell somehow.
Bunu hissetmiştim.
That's kind of sad, too!
Biraz hayal kırıklığı oldu!
The next time I come to this village,
Geri döndüğümde,
my stories will sound more unbelievable than any tall tale!
tamamen doğru olan daha abartılı hikâyeler anlatacağım!
Okay! I look forward to it!
Güzel! İple çekiyorum!
You guys take care, too!
Siz de kendinize iyi bakın!
Let's meet again sometime!
Bir ara tekrar görüşelim!
How come?
Niye?
Huh? "How come?"
Ha? "Niye mi?"
Man, would it kill you to play nice?
Biraz kibar olsan ölür müsün?
I'm gonna be a pirate too, so we'll meet on the high seas eventually!
Korsan olduğumuzdan bir gün yollarımız kesişebilir.
What're you talking about?
Ne saçmalıyorsun? Bin hadi.
What?
Ne?
You're one of us now, aren't you?
Biz bir ekibiz, değil mi?
I-I...
K-Kaptan...
I get to be captain, right?!
Kaptan olacağım, değil mi?!
Don't be dumb!
Aptal olma!
I'm the captain!
Kaptan benim!
There goes the captain...
Kaptan gidiyor.
Yeah.
Evet.
But he's with those guys, so I feel less worried now.
Evet ama onlarla gittiği için endişelenmiyorum.
Yeah.
Haklısın.
They're stronger than anyone I've ever seen.
Onlardan daha güçlüsünü görmedim.
It makes sense though.
Buraya kadar.
He always said he wanted to be a pirate.
Hep korsan olmak istediğini söylerdi.
The villagers won't be happy to hear it, though...
Ama köylüler bunu duyunca mutlu olmayacaklar...
It's all so sudden... He's the reason this place was so lively.
Hızlı oldu. Kaptan varken her şey çok canlı ve renkliydi.
I just had an idea!
Bir fikrim var!
– What is it?
– Nedir?
Merry...
Merry...
Yes?
Evet?
Lying is painful...
Yalan söylemek zormuş...
Are you referring to Klahadore?
Klahadore'u mu kastediyorsunuz?
No...
Hayır...
You mean how you actually wanted to stop Usopp from going?
Öyleyse Usopp-kun'un gitmesini gerçekten istemediniz, değil mi?
Miss...
Hanımefendi,
the villagers once told me a story from his childhood.
köylüler, onun çocukluğuna dair bana bir hikâye anlatmışlardı.
Shortly after Usopp's father ran off from the village,
Usopp-kun'un babası köyden ayrıldıktan kısa süre sonra,
his mother passed away.
annesi vefat etmiş.
The pirates are coming!
Korsanlar geliyor!
Dad's pirate ship is here!
Babamın korsan gemisi burada!
H-Hold on, Usopp!
S-Sakin ol, Usopp!
You mustn't shout!
Bağırmamalısın!
Dad came to pick us up!
Babam bizi almaya geldi!
D-Don't be silly... Usopp...
S-Saçmalamayı bırak, Usopp.
But he said he'd take us with him when you get better, Mom!
Ama sen iyileştiğinde bizi de götüreceğini söylemişti, anne!
Your father won't be coming back...
Baban geri dönmeyecek.
But... I'm proud to have married him...
Yine de... Onunla evlendiğim için gururluyum.
There's a miracle cure out there!
Dışarıda mucizevi bir ilaç var!
It can cure any illness!
Her hastalığı iyileştirebilir!
You're so silly...
Çok safsın...
You dream too much...
Fazla hayal kuruyorsun...
I don't care if I'm silly!
Safsam ne olmuş?!
Of course I dream!
Tabii ki hayal kuruyorum!
I'm the son of a pirate!
Çünkü ben bir korsanın oğluyum!
Grow up to be a brave man like your father...
Büyüdüğünde baban gibi cesur bir adam ol.
The pirates are coming!
Korsanlar geliyor!!!
Perhaps out of loneliness,
Belki de çaresizlikten,
he continued to shout it out after she passed.
annesinin ölümünden sonra da böyle bağırmaya devam etti.
All in the hopes that his father's pirate ship would one day be at the shore...
Bir gün, içinde babasının bulunduğu bir geminin kıyıda belirip...
that one day, he would come back for him.
onu almaya geleceğini umdu...!
The villagers say that lie of his also contains his wish.
Köylüler, o yalanın içinde onun arzusu olduğunu da söylüyor.
Pirates!
Korsanlar!!!
As someone who lost his own parents in this village,
Ailesini kaybetmiş biri olarak,
it's no wonder he couldn't ignore you when you lost yours.
sizin de aynı acıyı yaşadığınızı görünce, sessiz kalamaması anlaşılır.
You will need to grow stronger now, too!
Şu andan itibaren, daha güçlü olmalısınız.
To live up to everything he's done until today!
Bugüne kadar sizin için yaptıklarına layık olmanız için...!
Yes!
Olur!
To our new ship and crewmate!
Yeni gemimize ve yoldaşımıza!
– Cheers!
– Şerefe!
They said they weren't gonna die, that they would fight to live.
Bana ölmek için değil, yaşamak için dövüştüklerini söylediler.
Usopp's lies always spoke about the joy of living.
Usopp-san'ın yalanları, her zaman yaşama sevinciyle doluydu.
They cheered me up and told me to live!
Bana yaşama cesareti veriyordu.
Indeed.
Aynen öyle.
Here we go!
Başlıyoruz!
Are we really gonna do this?!
Bunu gerçekten yapacak mıyız?!
You bet! We're following in our captain's footsteps!
Elbette! Kaptanımızın coşkusunu sürdürmeliyiz!
– The pirates are comiiing!
– Korsanlar geliyor!!!
You know what, Merry?
Hey, Merry?
I'm going to be a doctor!
Ben, doktor olmak istiyorum!
What a wonderful ambition!
Bu harika bir hedef!